感谢字幕听译者：DuDu teytao
-3
■
-2
校译：Lingku    双语合成：Lingku
-1
■
干得好 伙计们
Well done boys.
看来我们早餐能吃到冰冷的寿司啦
It looks like ice cold sushi for breakfast.
不 不 孩子 在这里
No, no son. Over here.
看见狮子了吗 看看这只狮子 来抓狮子呀
See the lion, look at  the lion, you get the lion.
孩子 听着 你将来会长大 某天会长成像你爸爸一样
Now son, if you are going to grow up and be like your daddy someday
你要学会怎么搏斗呀
you got to learn how to fight.
好了 艾力提 我给你看样东西 好吗
Alakay, let me show you something, OK?
看见这个记号了么
You see this mark?
你和我是一样的
You and me are the same and when you're bigger,
你长大后 也会是领头狮子 就像你爸爸一样
you are gonna be alpha lion just like your daddy.
现在 让我看看你怎么搏斗 准备好了吗
Now, let me see you fight. Ready?
不 艾力提 别跳舞
No Alakay, no dancing.
你就是自得其乐 是吧
You just amuse yourself, don't you?
你真是个怪孩子 怪孩子
You are a strange kid. You are a strange man.
来吧 再试一次
Oh come on, let's try it again.
哦 艾力提
Oh,Alakay
别跳舞 停
Stop...stop it,stop it rigth now,don't going...
他们不像你期待的那样长大 真的很令人失望啊
It's so disappointing when they don't grow up the way you want it to.
哦 拜托 你不会又来找我挑战吧
Oh come on. You are not challenging me again, are you?
看看好的那一面嘛 在我把你打败了 代替你做领头狮子之后
Look on the bright side Zuba. After I defeat you and take over as alpha lion,
你就有更多的时间 来陪你的白痴儿子啦
you will have so much more time to spend with your pathetic excuse of a son.
在我把你打得落花流水之前 让我问问你
Before I kick your butt, let me ask you,
你究竟到底为什么想要当领头狮子
why do you even want to become the alpha lion?
我长得比较帅 发型比较酷 我看起来也比较聪明
I am better looking, I have better hair, I am deceivingly smart and...
还有 我想让大家都听我的
I want everyone else to do what I say.
数到三就开始 一...
We'll fight on three. One...
来 艾力提 好好看着
Pay attention Alakay.
看爸爸大显身手
Daddy gonna show you how it's done.
二 三!
Two, three.
- 谁是领头狮子? - 你是
Who is alpha lion? You are.
你可别忘了
Don't you forget it.
还有 艾力提 搏斗就是这个样子
And that Alakay is how you attack.
艾力提?
Alakay?
动物保护区 禁止狩猎
就是这个样子 来吧 孩子
That's it. Here kitty kitty.
这可是个漂亮的小家伙啊 肯定能值几个钱
Ah, this one is a beauty. It will be worth a few bucks.
封上 走吧
It just gets easier and easier.
- 爸爸! - 艾力提?
- Daddy! - Alakay?
艾力提,艾力提!
Alakay,Alakay!
爸爸!
Daddy!
不 不!
No, no, no!
艾力提!
Alakay!
- 爸爸! - 艾力提! 爸爸来了! 坚持一下
Daddy! Alakay! Daddy got you, hold on.
爸爸!
Daddy!
艾力提!
Alakay!
爸爸!
Daddy!
马达加斯加2:逃往非洲
Madagascar Escape 2 Africa
海上捕捞出幼狮
我不喜欢这家伙的样子
I don't like looks of this guy.
我觉得他还满可爱的呀
Well, I think he is kind of cute.
我觉得他太显摆自己了
I think he is kind of show off.
你觉得他可爱吗
You think he is cute?
纽约市之王
The king of New York City.
狮子艾力克斯!
Alex the lion!
我还是觉得他太显摆了
I still think he is kind of a show off.
肯定是的啊 他是动物嘛
You got to give it to him, the guy is an animal.
你拜托一下
Maybe you should take a break.
哎 你知道么 我们都去度个假也不错呀
You know, we could all use a vacation.
得了 我们能去哪度假
Come on. Where on earth would we go on vacation.
我不知道你想怎样 不过我想去康乃狄克州
I don't know about you but I wanna go to Connecticut.
几只动物 包括世界知名的
On the loose, several animals including the world famous...
狮子纽约之王艾力克斯 正在游荡中
...Alex the lion the king of New York...
它们是在今晚 从中央公园动物园逃脱的
escaped from the Central Park Zoo tonight.
逃脱者终于在中央火车站被抓到了
The escapees were finally cornered in Grand Central Station.
它是只坏 坏猫咪
It was a very bad kitty.
动物权力主义分子们 原本说服了动物园负责人
Animal rights activists who convinced zoo officials...
把这些逃脱的动物送去非洲
to have the escaped animals sent to Africa...
但今天这些运载动物的船只 被报导失踪
were stunned to learn that the shipping freighter carrying the animals...
令人十分震惊
was reported missing today.
今晚 许多纽约人都在中央公园汇聚
Tonight hundreds of New Yorkers have gathered at the Central Park Zoo...
为他们喜爱的动物们的丧生表示哀悼
to mourn the loss of their beloved zoo animals.
大家都在想的一个问题就是: 它们现在在哪?
The question on everyone's mind: where are they now.
#I like to move it, move it!
#He likes to move it, move it!
#She likes to move it, move it!
#We like to?
#Move it!
我们会想念你们的 小绒球们 你们是超棒的一群伙伴
We are gonna miss you little fuzz buckets. You guys had been a great crowd.
很荣幸能教会你们用马桶
Glad we can introduce you to the toilet.
如果你们有天来曼哈顿的话 别担心 打个电话就行
If you ever come to look at Central Manhattan, feel free to call first.
不过说真的 绝对要先打个电话 好吗
Seriously no, call. OK?
冷静下来 大家 安静
Settle down, settle down everybody. Ssh... Be quite.
你们不能没有这个就走了呀
You can't leave without this.
惊喜啊 怪咖们!
Hey. Surprise freaks! Look.
摇摆 摇摆
Shake it, shake it.
我是位女士 我是位女士 大家
Yeah, I am a lady, I am a lady everyone. I am a lady.
其实是我 朱利安国王
Not really, it's me, it's King Julien.
你们谁被我迷倒啦?
Which of you was attracted to me?
抬起手来
Hands up.
嘿 怪咖们 你们会很高兴听到 我会跟你们一起去!
Hey freaks! You will be very glad to hear that I am coming with you.
不了 谢谢
Oh no, thank you.
嗯 是的 谢谢 是我的飞机呀
Yes thank you. It's my plane.
我从新国家回来以前
Until I return with the spoils from the new country...
史提威就是老大
...Stevie will be in charge.
我觉得他们不太喜欢这个主意啊 朱利安
I don't think they liked that idea so much Julien.
你到底在说什么 史提威?
What is that you are saying Stevie?
哦! 不!
Oh, oh, no!
不 你没这么说 那根本不可能呀 哈哈
What? Really? No, you didn't say that. Oh it's not even possible.
Stevie says:
真淘气! 史提威说
让他们吃蛋糕
Let them eat the cake!
朱利安! 等等我!
King Julien wait for me.
我都已经收拾好了! 行程也计划好了
I'm all packed. I have such a whole itinerary plan.
哦 不! 默特!
Oh no. It's Mort.
- 他很烦人的!别让他上来! - 我好想放声欢唱呀
He's so annoying. Don't let him on.
别让他上来! 他携带了剪刀和护手霜!
Stop that thing, he is carrying scissors and hand cream.
好了好了 快点 上去 快点上去!
Everybody in quickly. Get in. Get in. Get in quick. Get in quick.
- 电力 - 检查完毕
Struts. Checked.
- 仪器 - 检查完毕
Fillets. Checked.
- 引擎 - 检查完毕
Engine. Checked.
- 开关? - 检查完毕
Coffee mate. Checked.
再见了 伙计们
Oopsie daisy.
这肯定是我这辈子我见过的 第二大的弹弓了
That is got to be the second biggest slingshot I have ever seen.
但不得不这么做了
But it is got to have to do. Attention.
注意 我是你们的机长
This is your captain speaking.
如果有紧急事件时
In the event of a water emergency,
把救生衣套在两边 然后说拜拜
place the vest over your head then kiss your life good bye!
- 纽约 我们来啦 宝贝儿! - 各位坐好 放松
- New York City, here we come baby.  - ...sit back, relax and pray your personal gods that...
祈祷这架私人垃机能飞起来
...this hunk of junk flies.
私人垃... 什么?
Personal god, hunk, what?
我们起飞吧
We are going sir.
把门打开 我还在外面!
Open the door. I am outside.
如果机舱内气压瞬间下降 请把面罩罩上
In case of losing cabin pressure, please place the mask over your face...
好让其他乘客 不被你惊吓的表情吓坏
to hide your terrified expressions from the other passengers.
不好意思 小姐 但这个不是应该
Excuse me miss. But aren't these supposed...
- 连着我的座位的么 - 不是的 先生
- to be attached to my seat. - No sir.
好吧 小伙子们 发射!
OK. boys. Launch.
发射! 发射! 发射!
Launch. Launch. Launch.
谢谢你们 怪咖
Melman!
嗨 默特
Hey, Mort.
哎。。。
Hi.
- 真奇怪 - 嘿 有人在做梦了 啊?
That was weird. Hey, somebody is dreaming ha?
我好像刚刚在飞机的机翼上 看到默特了
I think I just saw Mort on the wing of the plane.
你太想念马达加斯加了
You got Madagascar on the brain.
是啊 太美妙了
... it was quite a, it was incredible, wasn't it?
我觉得我们走越远 越能回想到更多的乐趣
I think we will see much more fun the further way we get from.
回想什么 你咬我的屁股吗
Yeah, like when you beat me on the butt?
我要把这个 你一直说的这件事
I am gonna take that, that thing you are holding on to...
在舞台上用
...and I am going to use it, on stage.
全都变成 像我的演员沙拉吧一样的 就像活动小报 其中之一
So all part of my little actor's salad bar of emotional tidbits.
所有的"屁股小吃" 都在沙拉吧的油面包旁边吗
Are the butts next to the crutons at the salad bar?
- 你没必要讽刺啊 马蒂 - 嘿 大家 我正在想
- You don't need to be sarcastic Marty. - Hey guys, you know, I was thinking.
我们回去的时候 我没准可以报名参加那个繁殖计划
When we get back, I might assign up for the breeding program.
- 繁殖计划? - 我觉得我们都到了一把年纪了
- Breeding program? - I think we all reach a point on our lives...
我们应该遇到某个人 安定下来 交往交往
when we wanna meet somebody, you know settle down, have a relationship.
什么 你是说
I see that. What?
- 像是 约会吗 - 是啊 约会!
- Like, like dating? - Yeah, dating!
其他的 其他的... 男生?
Other, other... Other guys?
你是什么意思 其他的男生?
What do you mean "other guys"?
哎呀
Darn it!
我要去看看 饮料怎么来的这么慢
I'm gonna, what is holding up that beverage service.
我要去看看
I'm gonna go and check.
嗯 你们大家继续聊 我要先打一下盹儿
Oh, yeah ya, keep talking. I'm gonna catch a few wings.
你看到了吗 好好笑哦
Did you see that? It is so funny.
我爱大笑
I like laughing.
感觉真不错 笑呀
It is such a nice experience. To laugh.
不好意思 我想你得往回走 这里是一等舱
Do you mind going back? This is first class.
没什么针对你个人的 只是说 我们比你好而已
It's nothing personal, it's just that we are better than you.
嘿 莫里斯 快呀 快啊
Hey Maurice. I'm awful, hit me, hit me.
- 那是吧台吗 - 飞行奴隶
- Is it Vivaldi? - It's nothing personal, it's just that we are better than you.
我能怎么帮你呢 先生
Can I help you Mr. Mankiewicz?
给我干果 用银盘子装
Bring me my nuts, on a silver plate.
我们只是想看看 我们点的饮料怎么样了
We just wanted to check on the drinks we ordered.
真对不起 有点太忙了
Oh, sorry. We are in a little backed up.
- 我猜我就回去吧 - 嘿 你身体怎么啦 真令我不舒服
- Then I guess I am gonna back to..  - Hey, what happened to your body? You are freaking me out.
你能不能请到那边去呢 多谢你啦
And can you please go over there please. Thank you very much.
等级区分这件事到底还存不存在啊
Whatever happened to the separation of the classes.
那些什么民主的东西 只是一时的啦
Yeah, I am sure is all democracy thing is just affeered.
你要不要一点菠萝呢 我的小可爱
老大 你看
Skipper, look.
- 分析分析 - 这看起来很小的灯泡
- Analysis. - It looks like a small incandescent bulb designed to
应该是有什么不寻常的东西 比如机械故障
indicate something out of the ordinary. Like a malfunction.
- 我倒是觉得它很漂亮 而且有点催眠 - 知道了 长官
I found it pretty and somewhat hypnotic. That too sir.
瑞哥 手册拿来
Right. Rico, manual.
- 问题解决了 - 长官 我们的燃料可能不够了
Problemo solved. Sir, we may be out of fuel.
- 你为什么会这么觉得呢 - 我们的一号引擎已经不工作了
- What makes you think that?  - We lost engine one.
二号引擎也没火了
And engine two is no longer on fire.
伙计们 系好安全带
Buckle up boys.
别看 娃娃 这可能会变得很残忍
Don't look dull. This might get hairy. Attention.
注意 我是机长
This is your captain speaking.
我有好消息 也有坏消息
I've got good news and bad news.
好消息就是 我们马上就要降落了
The good news is, we will be landing immediately.
坏消息是
The bad news is...
我们会是坠落的
we are crush landing!
当你们要航空旅行时 我们知道 你们别无选择
When it comes to air travel, we know you have no choice what so ever.
但还是要谢谢你们选择企鹅航空
But thanks again for choosing air penguin.
把双手举起来 莫里斯
Raise your arms Maurice.
这样举着更好玩呀
It's more fun when you raise your arms like this.
我能飞耶!
I can fly.
我们可能这样就完了 马蒂
This could be it Marty.
但我还是想说 你是个真正的朋友 百万里挑一的
I just want you to know that you are truly a one in a million friend.
谢谢 伙计 你是最棒的 永远都是
Thanks buddy. You are the best ever.
我知道如果我告诉你 你不会介意的
I know you won't mind when I tell you...
告诉我啊 告诉我什么
Come on. Tell me it, tell me, tell me what?
- 我把你的iPod弄坏了 - 什么?!
- I broke your iPod! - What!
按键太小了嘛 我受不了...
The button were so small.
- 太恐怖了 - 对不起嘛
- It made me mad. - I'm sorry.
- 我要杀了你! - 是个意外嘛 对不起啦
I'm gonna kill you!
我爱你 格洛丽娅 一直都爱
I love you Gloria, I always have!
就像爱海滩一样... 或者一本好书...
Like ah... Like you love the beach or a good book.
或者海滩
Or the beach.
天呀 娃娃 你像叶子一样颤抖
My goodness doll, you are shaking like a leaf.
瑞哥 你玩过瘾了 拉上去吧!
Rico, you had your fun. Haul up!
放下轮子
Gear down.
好 现在我们要稍微亲一下地面
Gently now. You just wanna kiss the ground.
小小的亲而已 蜻蜓点水那种
Just a little pack, smooch like a kiss...
我说亲而已!
I said kiss it!
现在踩踩煞车 轻轻的踩
Now, just a little break. Just a touch, a little whisper.
我相信 现在我要将军了
I believe that's checkmate.
操作紧急降落步骤 襟翼向上!
Immersed emergency landing procedure.
展开!
Flaps up! Deploy!
哦 我们终于... 嗯?
Oh, we are here.
这是怎么回事?
What in the world?
飞机怎么了
What happened to the plane?
- 飞机坠毁了 好了 我还活着 - 我不知道
OK. I'm OK. OK. I'm alive.
我连好好睡觉都不行吗
See, I can't even sleep for a minute.
你知道么 这里也不是纽约肯尼迪机场
You know what, this is not JFK.
科沃斯基 伤亡报告
Kowalski, casualty report.
只有两名乘客不知去向 机长
Only two passengers unaccounted for, Skipper.
这个数字我可以接受 着陆不错 伙计们!
That's a number I can live with.Good landing boys.
谁说企鹅不能飞了?
Who says a penguin can't fly.
嘿 打得火热的人们 有什么可庆祝的 看看这个飞机!
Hey, happy slappers. Is there some reason to celebrate? Look at the plane. We'll fix it.
- 我们会修好的 - 修好? 你怎么修这个?
- Fix it?  - How you gonna fix this?
他 口水 还有很多布基胶带
Grit, spit and a whole lotta duct tape.
我们应该可以完成 时间大概需要...
We should be up and running in say,
- 6到9个月 - 69个月?
- six to nine months. - Sixty nine months?
不是 是6到9个月
No! Six to nine months.
科沃斯基 我觉得我们要化困境为优势
Kowalski,  I say we use this setback to our advantage.
你怎么计算出这个数字的? 嗯?
Where do you get, where do you pull that number out of, huh?
我想让你把整个设计重新改造 现在开始
I want you to reconfigure the design, so start reconfiguring! Great, that's a great...
- 你怎么能预估呢? - 你 小白脸
- How do you estimate that? - You! Pretty boy!
要不然你和你的朋友们去挖树 找找水
Why don't you and your friends dig a tree, maybe find water.
等一下 等等 谁说你可以当这个...
Hold on, hold on a second. Who made you...
飞机残骸之王了?
king of the plane wreck?
啊? 你说什么? 行啊
Excuse me. Fine,
你来指挥吧 你来修飞机啊
you can be in charge. You fix the plane!
谁给你的权力 让我来指挥的?
Who gives you the authority to put me in charge?
那好吧 我继续指挥
OK then, I'll remain in charge.
对了 你继续指挥
Yeah, that's right.
你和你的嘻皮朋友们最好离我们的空气远点
You will remain in charge. You and your little happy friends can stay out of our hair.
没错! 就是这样!
Correctamundo!
- 因为是我决定这么做的! - 不错 不错
- Because I decided to.  - Good for you.
哦 是吗 你知道吗 这个谈话还没结束
Yeah, well guess what this discussion isn't over.
嘿 动物们 你们可以跟我们在一起
Higher mammals, you stay with us.
我们可以用一下你们的头皮 和可吸吮的拇指
We could use your front cortexes and apposable thumbs.
菲尔 我该让你用肥皂洗一洗手的
Feel crushed wash your hands out with soap.
怎么会...? 喂! 他们到底会不会修这个飞机啊
How, in the.. Hello! are they gonna fix this plane?
你知道吗 补破皮褥子不如不补破皮褥子
You know, grit 'n spit and spit, once spit and griten.
- 我们就等吧 - 听起来没啥希望
Stick to it at mist. They don't sound too promising.
你是对的 是对的 我们被困在这里了
You're right. Right, we are stuck here.
嘿 大家 只要我们在一起 我们就没事的
Hey guys, as long as we're together we'll be OK.
是啊 是啊 但这不能送我们回家啊
Yeah, yeah but love ain't gonna get us home.
宽广的大地
Behold, the lion!
- 哇 人类! - 好啦 还有很多要看的 赶快走吧
- Hey, it's people.  - OK. There is much to see, moving on.
人! 人们! 等等!
People. Wait, wait.
人们! 停下
Wait people.
救救我们
Help us!
喂 等等
Hi! Wait!
如果你们停下 我可以帮你们签名啊
Hey wait, if you stop we'll autograph those.
我认识你
I know you.
- 你 - 是那只坏猫咪
You. It's that bad kitty.
感觉如何呀?
How do you like some other?
我在东京???
Are you in Tokyo?
正中要害
Right in the batteries!
你以为一位老太太不能自己照顾自己吗?
You think that old lady can't take care of you?
下次我再遇见你 就不会像这次一般手软了
Next time I won't go so easy on you.
谢谢 亲爱的
Thank you dear.
继续游览!
Moving on.
你疯了吗 我们需要他们的帮助啊
Are you out of your mind? We need their help,
你却去骚扰一个小老太太?
and you're arresting little old ladies?
我疯了? 哈哈 看看 现在是谁疯了啊
Out of my mind? Aha! Who is out of my mind?
- 看看能不能联络到接线员 - 没问题
See if you can get an operator? No problem.
我疯了? 我们要回家了
Out of my mind? We're going home.
信息: 用户在服务区外
Message A-4: the service user has brought outside of the coverage area.
请稍后再试
Please try again later.
哦 天啊
Oh my.. Wow...
我不是嗑药了吧
Am I trappen?
那些是斑马 像我一样!
All those zebras, like me.
- 等等 我们在哪? - 圣地亚哥
Wait a minute, where are we? San Diego.
这次我有40%确定
This time I'm forty percent sure.
- 我知道这个地方 - 我觉得这是非洲
- I know this place. - I think this is Africa.
- 非洲? - 肯定是的
- Africa? - It's gotto be.
我们祖先的地盘
Our ancestral crib.
在我们的血液里 我能感受到!
It's in our blood. I can feel it.
不 这比那更多 就好像
No, no. It's more than that.
似曾相识 好像 好像我来过这里
It's like dejavu. Like I've, like I've been here before.
- 就像根一样! - 不 不
It's like roots. No, no.
这...这就好像似曾相识 好像 好像我来过这里
It's like dejavu. Like I've, like I've been here before.
我 艾力克斯 我和我朋友们
Me, Alex. Me and me friends.
飞 飞 在一个很大的金属鸟里
Fly. Fly. In great metal bird.
突然间
Then. Plummet.
砸到地上 轰!
Smash ground. Go boom.
然后 这里 我们 就出现了
Then here. We emerge.
我们只想带来 快乐 和 问侯
We offer only happiness and good greetings.
他是在为那个飞机失事跳舞么
Is he dancing about a plane crash.
是啊 是啊 我还以为... 对不起
Yeah, we just... Yeah. I thought. Sorry.
你是说你是从保护区之外的地方来的吗
You mean, you came from off the reserve.
是啊 很远以外 事实上 是从中央公园动物园来的
Yeah, way off, from the Central Park Zoo actually.
别太使劲了
Don't strain yourself.
发生什么事了 大家这是在干什么
What is going on here, what is all this have about?
他们说 他们是从保护区之外的地方来的
They say they are from off the reserve.
这是不可能的 只有人类会从保护区外进来
That's impossible. Only people come from off the reserve.
你看起来很面熟 我们见过吗...?
You look familiar, do I know you from...
你怎么可能逃过那些猎人?
How could you possibly survived the hunters.
- 猎人? 我们倒是没见过什么猎人 - 你在看什么?
- Hunters, we didn't see any hunters. - What are you looking at?
我吗? 什么也没看
Me? Nothing.
这里的水和食物不需要更多的嘴来抢食了
This watering hole doesn't need any more mouths to feed.
所以就回去你原来的地方 好吗
So just get out of back to wherever you came from.
好吧 有没有什么经理可以出来说说话的
OK. Was there a maybe like a manager we can talk to?
哦 我知道了 你是来跟我挑战的!
Oh, I see. You're here to challenge me.
啊 什么? 不是 不是
What? No! No, no.
- 我看起来就像是这么回事! - 等等
- What else would start you look on to me? - Hold on
祖巴 等等
Zuba, wait.
唉 女人 你看不出来我在干什么吗
Don't call woman, don't you see I am trying...
- 你不能就... - 嗯 嗯 祖巴 等等
Yeah, yeah... Zuba. Hold on.
艾力提
Alakay
- 是你吗 - 不 我叫艾力克斯
- is that you? - No, it's Alex.
克斯 就像纽约尼克斯篮球队一样?
"X",  like New York Knicks.
祖巴 看看
- Zuba, look.
我一直都有这个 你看吧
Oh, I have always had that, have had checked it out, it's really...
嗯 其实有点像美人痣一样 真的
it's kind of a beauty spot, really.
记号?
Mark.
好吧 有点怪怪的
Alright, this is a little weird.
亲爱的 他回家了
Honey, he has come home.
什么?
What?
你回家来了
You've come home.
儿子
Son.
爸爸?
Dad.
妈妈? 爸爸?
Mom and dad.
Mom and dad. It's my mom and dad.
我有妈妈和爸爸了!
I've got a mom and dad.
哦孩子还活着
My baby is alive.
爸爸
Dad
我的儿子!
My son.
我的儿子回家了!
My son is home.
艾力提! 艾力提回家了!
Alakay! Alakay is home!
艾力提 耶!
Alakay, yeah.
失踪的儿子回来了 这真是太完美了
The pathetical son returns. This is perfect.
我还以为你讨厌祖巴呢
I thought you hated Zuba.
不 我确实是
No I do. I do, I do.
我恨 我讨厌他
I hate him. Oh, I do.
我要利用艾力提! 对了!
And I am going to use Alakay. Yes.
我要利用他把祖巴永远的铲除掉!
I am going to use him to get rid of Zuba once and for all.
让开 让开! 站边上!
Move out of the way, stand aside.
这里有点像垃圾车 你确定我们不在纽泽西吗
New York. Hmm, it's a bit of a dumb. Are you sure we are not in New Jersey?
你好! 纽约客们! 你们新的大王到了!
Hello New Yorkers, your new king is here.
这些全部都是在庆祝吗?
This calls for celebration.
莫里斯 我想他们喜欢我
Maurice, I think they like me.
你要接管一个王国 肯定得让他们喜欢你呀
You got to love a known house to take off.
Chaka chaka what?
不好意思 不好意思 我叫马蒂
Excuse me, excuse me. I'm Marty.
我在这附近算新人
I'm kind of new around here.
- 嘿 马蒂! - 嘿!
- Hey Marty. - Hey!
你们这个组还真好看呀
you are a good looking group.
你们喜欢跑步吗
You like to run?
哦 当然 跑步超屌的!
Oh yeah. Running is crackalacking.
没错! 超屌的!
That's right, that's right, crackalacking.
你们跟我说同一种超屌的语言呀
You guys are speaking my crackalacking language.
啊? 你们这里竟然没有医生?
What, you don't have doctors here?
嗯 不再有了
Well, not any more.
如果你感冒了呢
What if you catch a cold?
我们去那个等死洞待着 然后 我们死
We go over to the die holes and we die.
你们真的需要一位医生
OK, you guys really need a doctor.
- 嘿 我们倒是有个空缺呀 - 你有兴趣么
- Hey, we have an opening. - Would you be interested?
我? 当医生?
Me? A doctor?
天上掉男人呀 哈里路亚 唉 真的想回家
It's raining men, hallelujah. You are gotto going all.
为什么你的生命中没有个男人呢
How come you don't have a man in your life.
你有虫子么
You got worms?
我都弄掉了啦 听着 女孩们
Listen girls
曼哈顿有两种东西短缺: 停车位 和 河马
Manhattan is short on two things: parking and hippos.
嘿 大家 我才知道 我的儿子也是一方霸主
Hey everybody! I just found out that my son is a king.
他是纽约之王!
The king of New York.
来 给我看看你的动作 别害羞
Show me some of your moves son. Come on. Don't be bashful. Alright.
哦 这个通常会让人拍手叫好
Ooh, this one always knocks them dead.
大王发怒了 大王发怒了!
The king is mad, the king is mad.
现在 让我们一起欢迎他 回到我们的部落吧 张开双臂!
Now, let's all welcome him back into the pride above the arms.
欢迎你来到我们的群呀 马蒂
Welcome to the herd Marty.
我? 群? 我一直都想加入某个群呢!
Me, in a herd? I've always wanted to be a part of a herd.
- 有一个是大家的 - 就都是大家的 呦!
It's one for all, and all for all.
- 我看起来怎么样? - 理论上说
- How do I look?  - Technicly...
一个传统的巫医 通常都有根骨头穿过鼻子
a traditional witch doctor has a bone to his nose.
别担心 只是个夹上去的而已
Don't worry, it has just a clip on it.
呵呵 他是个巫医了!
Voila, he's a witch doctor.
我母亲一定会很高兴的
My mother would be so happy.
看看 我觉得 摩托摩托喜欢你哦
Look out. I think Moto Moto likes you.
他过来了
Here he comes.
#I like 'em big.
#I like 'em chunky.
#I like 'em plumpy.
#I like 'em round.
#With something, something.
#They like my sound. They think I'm funky.
喂 女孩 你够壮的啊
Goodness girl. You're huge.
你的朋友是谁呀? 或者那是你的屁股?
Who is your friend, or is that your butt?
你反应倒是真快
Girl, you are as quick as you all have to.
所以 你叫摩托摩托?
So, you are Moto Moto.
这么好听的名字 当然要说两次
The name is so nice, when you say it twice.
- 我还挺喜欢的 猛男 - 再见吧 女孩
- I kind of a like it that so. - I see you around new.
但不会很难的 因为你好... 丰满
I won't be hard, because you're so plumpy.
我真的很不喜欢扫兴 祖巴
Oops. I hate to be a party pooper Zuba...
但部落里其它的狮子想问问
but some of the other lions are wondering...
你什么时候才会把你的儿子流放走
when you are going to banish your son.
你到底在说什么 麻昆加?
What are you talking about, Makunga?
其实也没什么 真的 他们只是在碎碎念
It's nothing really,if their great being about who...
艾力提并没有遵循 正统的通过仪式什么的
Alakay never went through the rite of passage, bla bla bla...
所以 理论上说
So, technically speaking...
他并不能成为部落的一员 于礼不合的
...he can't be a member of the pride, it's nonsense.
我都忘了有通过仪式了
I had forgotten about the rite of passage.
那是什么? 什么通过 什么仪式啊
What is it? What is this rite of passage?
是个祖先传下来的传统
It's a traditional common of a ceremony...
年轻的狮子可以 表演他们的技术 来换取他们的地位
where young lions earn their manes by demonstrating their skills.
表演技术? 像歌唱表演那种吗?
Sort of a show skill, talent show, tab dale?
是呀 全投入就好了
Yeah, sturdiness stuff.
太棒了 表演! 虽然不是我的强项
Great informers. I think that's up my alley guys.
不过既然是传统 我想做做看
If it's tradition, I want to do it.
打给他们看看 让我的鬃毛 得到应有的尊重 我想当艾力凯
Stud my stuff. Earn my mane. I want to be Alakuy.
- 艾力提 - 艾力提 还要更好
- Alakay. - Alakay. Even better.
明天一大早 我们就举行通过仪式
We'll hold the rite of passage first thing in the morning.
太棒了 祝你好运 艾力提
That's wonderful. Good luck Alakay.
在我以前的地方 我们会说"表演成功"
Where I come from we say: Break a leg.
这才是我的儿子
Oh, that's my boy.
真美 不是吗
Beautiful, isn't it?
- 是啊 - 太美妙了
- Yeah. - It's amazing.
大家 这才是我们真正属于的地方
Guys, this is where we belong.
"旅客陷阱行动"马上就要开始了
Operation tourist trap is in go.
哦 这句话说的好 真的好
Oh, I like that one. That's a good one.
很多方面都是这样
That works on many levels sir.
你们两个真是马屁精!
You guys are a bunch of suck ups.
- 这也是实话 - 绝对的
- That too sir. - Absolutely.
各就各位
Hide. Stations.
第一步 去!
Stage one. Go.
哦 不! 我都做了些什么?
Oh no. What've I done.
来吧 上钩
Come on, take the bait.
- 怎么办 怎么办 - 它死了吗
第二步 伙计们 走 走!
Stage two. Go, go, go.
我会给他生命之吻
I'll  give him the kiss of life.
瑞哥
Rico.
瑞哥!
Rico!
倒车档! 油门! 音乐!
Reverse. Gas. Music.
停车! 停车!
Oh no, stop. Stop.
停车! 回来!
Stop. Come back.
这些是什么烂摇滚乐?
What is all that rock'n roll racket?
她死了吗
Is she dead?
没有
No!
强盗!
You hood ones!
你没事吗
Good heavens. Are you OK?
女士 我找到了你的手提包
Lady, I found your pocket bag.
我的手提包! 你真是个好孩子
Oh, my hand bag. Such a good boy.
没有它 娜娜不能生活的
Man, I can't survive without it.
您真强悍啊
Wow, you are a one tough cookie.
女童子军 第2416号 铜章
Brownies, root for sixteen. Yonkers.
好了 大家别紧张
OK. Nobody panic.
现在最明智的选择就是呆在一起
The best thing we can do is stay together.
等下一辆游览车
We'll wait for another tour jeep.
可能需要几个小时 天色也开始暗了...
It may take hours and it's getting dark but...
你去哪啊
Where are you going?
我可不想露天站着 等动物来攻击我们
I'm not gonna stay out in the opening get attacked by more animals.
我太老了 还不想死
I'm too old to die.
我不知道你们要怎么样 但我要跟她一起走
I don't know about you guys but I'm going with her.
老太太 等等我们
Oh,Lady! Wait us!
拜托! 我们要... 在... 一起
Please! We need to stay... together.
算了 就往那走吧
Fine, we'll go that way.
有人想吃热糖么
Does anyone want a hot candy?
小心脚步
Easy now. Watch your step.
而就是这里了
And this, right here.
准备好了吗
OK. Are you ready?
你一直都睡这
This is where you always slept.
哦 哇
Oh man!
- 这个以前是我的吗 - 玩吧 亲爱的
- Was this mine? - Look at you. Look at him honey.
哦 这个东西 看看! 我记得它!
Oh my. Oh this thing. Look, look. I remember this.
你记得?
You remember.
- 这比我期待的要硬了点... - 你从来不在这睡的
- Harder than I... - You never slept on the right end.
最后都滚到底下去
You always slept on the bottom end.
那 那是不是我的...
Was that, was that my?
那是我吗
Is that me?
你的小爪子是最可爱的
You had the cutest little paws.
很小 很小的小爪子
Little bit of paws.
这就是我们失去你那天 你印上去的
You did that the day we lost you.
是啊
Year!
哇 我当时很小啊
Wow. I was so young.
在我身上发生了什么事?
What happened to me?
是我的错 我转过身了 就那么一秒...
It was all my fault. I turned my back for a minute and...
那不是你的错
It was not your fault.
你爸爸真的尽力了
Your father did everything he could.
他跟踪了那些猎人整整好几周
He tracked those hunters for weeks.
- 离保护区很远很远 - 最后 我也只好认为
Far off the reserve. Finally I had to assume that the hunters... Well...
我们以为... 我们以为他们把你杀了
We thought, we thought they killed you.
但我的儿子把那些猎人都打垮了是不是?
But my son fought those hunters off ha?
别跟纽约之王作对!
Don't mess with the king of New York.
没错!
That's right.
好啦 好啦 大男孩 小心点
Alright, alright boys. Be careful.
别打碎了东西
Watch out before you break something.
你以前管这个叫 "扑扑"
You used to call this Fufi.
扑扑? 扑扑!
Fufi? Fufi.
- 他不会想要那个的 - 还给我 我的扑扑!
Oh, he doesn't want that thing. Give my Fufi.
祖巴 你最好把他的扑扑给他
Zuba, you'd better give him his Fufi.
我并不知道... 谢谢 谢谢 它很完美
I mean no, thank you, thank you. It's perfect.
那 儿子 休息吧
Well son, you get your rest...
明天将会是盛大的一天 你会需要全部的力量
you'll have a big day tomorrow.You're gonna need all your strength.
我会为了你 让欢呼声把屋顶掀起来的
I'm gonna bring the house down for you dad.
我也这么希望 要不然你的父亲必须要流放你了
I hope so, otherwise your father would have to banish you.
哦 天 真的吗
Oh gee, not really?
我知道你会让我们骄傲的
I know you're gonna do us proud.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
你命中注定就是这样
You were born with it.
晚安 艾力提
Good night Alakay.
我的孩子 我自己的孩子
My boy, my own boy.
我的儿子是个大王
My son is a king.
晚安 妈妈
Good night mom.
晚安 艾力提
Good night,Alakay.
扑扑!
Fufi!
扑扑 我的扑扑!
Fufi! My Fufi!
扑扑! 扑扑! 我的扑扑!
Fufi! Fufi! My Fufi!
没有任何人类文明的征兆
No sign of civilization.
大家都很累 我觉得我们迷路了
Everybody appears very tired. I think we're lost.
嘿 娜娜 你知不知道你在往哪走啊
Hey Nana, do you even know where you are going?
不知道 不过我一路小跑 面带笑容
No, but I'm going with a skip in my step and a smile on my face.
哦 是嘛 那好吧
Sure, right, OK. Yeah, alright.
- 哦 是人啊 你们从哪来的 - 你们怎么到这里来的
It's people. Where do you come from? How could we get out of here?
你们能帮帮我们吗 我们迷路了
Can you help us, we're lost?
我们也迷路了
We are lost too.
真的很可怕 一个黑白的东西 掠过我们眼前 然后就没了
It was awful, a flash of black and white never gone.
他们把吉普车 所有东西都拿走了
They took the jeep, everything.
- 我们的吉普车也一样 - 我们要怎么办
- That happened to our jeep too. - What are we gonna do?
- 我们要怎么存活 - 没有食物
Only hope to survive out here! No food,
没有水 没有屋子 我们该怎么办呀!?
no water, no shelter. What are we gonna do?
你可以让大自然征服你
You can let nature get the best of you,
或者你可以征服大自然呀
or you can get the best of nature.
围过来吧 孩子们
Gather around children.
- 都是纽约客 是吧 - 是啊
- We are New Yorkers, right? - Yeah.
我们都能在水泥林里生存了!
We survived in a concrete jungle.
没错
Right!
我们饿的时候 就四处找 好吃的热狗 我说的对吗
If we need food, we hunt for a decent hotdogs stand, am I right?
她是对的
She is right.
我们需要屋子 就盖起摩天大楼
If we need shelter, we build skyscrapers.
- 是啊 - 我们需要水
If we need water,
就建造一个人工水库
we build a dam.
是啊! 我们是纽约客耶! 拜托一下!
Come on, we're New Yorkers.
我们在那里可以 我们哪里都可以!
If we can make it there, we can make it anywhere.
我来了 朱利安国王
I'm coming King Julien.
鱼 小鱼
Fish! Fish!
鲨鱼 不
No! Shark!
老大 所有的零件我们都有了
Skipper, we have all the parts we need...
可我们还是比计划稍稍迟了一点
but we're slightly behind schedule.
- 多迟? - 6到9年
- How slightly?  - Six to nine years.
- 69年? - 不是 是6到9年
- Sixty nine years?  - No six to nine years.
大兵 我们的拇指呢
Privates, what happened to our thumbs?
从昨天就没看见他们了
Haven't seen them since yesterday sir. Damn you...
在我眼皮底下 谁都不能去
Nobody goes AWOL on my watch.
大兵 跟我一起走
Private, you are coming with me.
瑞哥 你跟我一起来
Rico, you are coming with me.
追踪他 让他跟我军事法庭见
I'm tracking down to bring them for the court marshall.
没有必要啦
That won't be necessary.
我们为你多聘请了一些拇指 队长
We have recruited a few extra thumbs for you, Skipper.
- 有你们的帮忙太好了 - 我严重怀疑
- Floppy of monkeys entered. -I doubt that.
先慢点玩闹 我们开始工作吧 我们分成3组
Enough wallin' gagging now let's get to work. We'll divide into three groups.
A组 你们负责运输和加工
Group alpha, you are charged in seeping of fabrication.
B组 你们负责装配 C组 你们负责售后服务
Group Offset, you'll handle assembly. Group George Report: you'll handle gas services.
有问题吗?
Any questions?
真不错 开始工作吧
Good, then let's get to work.
我真想亲亲你 猴子
I'd like to kiss you monkey man.
好吧 但你也太丑了
Alright but you are so darn ugly.
好吧 带点气势 就记住
Alright, so little cubs cats, just remember...
伟大的舞蹈都是由心出发的
great dance performance comes from the heart.
由心出发 你永远也不会错
Just comes straight from your heart and you never go wrong.
当然
Sure Mr.
嘿 艾力提 我只是经过 祝你好运
Hey Alakay, I just happened to walk by and wanted to wish luck.
你不紧张吧
You're not nervous, are you?
不啦 就等这一天了 我本来也是干这个的
No, it's my thing. You know.It's kind of what I do.
我觉得 如果要在这里大显身手 要记得 选择好的对手
In my opinion; the key of this whole thing is choosing the right competitor.
你说这像跳舞对决一样的吗 像对舞一样
Oh, you mean this is like a dance battle, sort of thing? Like a dance off?
- 嗯 当然 - 那太好了 即兴创造?
- Sure. Great, I loved that. - Freestyle, put your moves out.
你觉得谁跟我旗鼓相当? 这样比赛才有看头
Who do you thing would be a good match for me? You know, just to keep the things interesting.
我真希望我能帮忙
Well...I wish I could help,
但这违反了传统啊 好像很神圣的样子
but that's strictly against to our ancient tradition and although we hold secret but
但如果是我的话
If I was me out there,
我会选择缇西
I'd choose Titsy.
缇西? 好吧 听起来... 还蛮有趣的
Titsy, OK?  Sounds interesting.
- 你叫麻昆加 对吧 - 为了祖巴的孩子 做任何事都好
- Makunga, right? Thank you.  - Anything for Zuba's boy.  Go, get him tight.
- 去露一手吧 - 一定的
Shake it out.
5678 来吧 放马过来
Come 5678,come on
通过仪式正式开始
Let us begin the rite of passage ceremony.
来吧 孩子 让妈妈骄傲!
Come on baby, make mama proud.
- 先等会 先让我说完... - 听到了 妈妈!
- Oh woman, I'm trying to take care of passage here. - Got it mom.
- 所以谁想第一个来? - 我 我!
- So who will be the first participant?  - Me, me me...
要不然你来吧 这个高高帅帅的孩子
How about you, the tall, handsome one? Right there, yeah.
请选择你的对手
Choose your opponent.
让我看看
Let me see.
我想 我还是选...
I guess I'll pick...
缇西?
...Titsy.
Titsy?
他为什么会选择缇西呢
Why did he pick Titsy?
哦 那就是我的孩子 他真有胆量
Oh, that's my boy, he got some gumption there.
有没有人把他叫醒 叫醒啊
Somebody wake him up, wake him up.
哦 是缇西吧 来呀 让他们看看 来吧
Alright, so Titsy. Come on. Let's do this ha?
来吧 缇西
Come on Titsy fly, Titsy fly,
看看你有什么本事 显出来嘛
come on let's see your stuff.Bring it.
开跳吧
Let's dance.
嗯 不过我要事先警告你 我可是狐步舞
OK. But it's only fair to warn you that...
和罗宾逊舞蹈教室的得意门生哦
I'm a prodigy of fupsy and robbins.
不是那个舞蹈 是搏斗
Not dance dance, fight.
舞斗是吗? 了解了
Oh, dance fight. You got it.
- 他是在跳舞吗 - 他在做什么
- Is he dancing?  - What is he doing?
我不知道 不过那个孩子确实是在跳舞
I know that boy is not dancing.
这比我想象的还要好
This is even better than I thought.
- 艾力提 回头! - 不 爸爸
- Alakay, turn around. - No no pap,
是往左挥 往右挥 扭扭屁股 再回头
it's hop shuffle ball change, hip swish, turn around.
哦 不
Oh no.
艾力提 你受伤了么
Alakay. Are you hurt?
哦 是啊
Oh yeah, I'm.
我赢了么
Did I, did I win?
不 孩子 这怎么会这样呢
Oh no son, how could, I mean how could this happen?
你告诉我们你是个大王
You told us you were a king.
大王是不会被打倒的
And a king does not get beat.
我确实是大王啊 我是纽约之王
Well, I'm a king. I'm a king in New York.
那是我的艺名 你知道
It's my stage name. I'm like a, you know,
我表演的时候用的
It's for what I perform.
表演?
Perform?
哦 真是太不幸了 艾力提没能通过测试
No, this is horrible. Alakay has failed the test.
谁会想得到 有朝一日
Who would have ever imagine that the day...
祖巴会必须流放...
Zuba would have to banish...
他自己的儿子?
...his own son.
祖巴 不要
Zuba, no.
祖巴 要
Zuba, yes.
悲伤的是 现在领头狮子 必须驱逐自己的心头肉
Sadly the alpha lion must cast out all failures.
那我不再是领头狮子了
Then, I'm no longer the alpha lion.
爸爸 你在做什么 爸爸 别这样
Dad, what are you doing?
爸爸 你不能这么做的
Dad no, you can't do this.
谁能顶替祖巴的位子呢?
Who could possibly take Zuba's place?
有人吗 任何人吗
Anyone? Someone?
- 没人吗 - 嘿
- No one? - Hey.
你吗 先生?
You sir.
看来不行
I guess not.
呃 虽然这么说很奇怪 不过
Well I, this is all very awkward, but...
我想 我能担负起这个重任
I suppose, I could carry this tremendous burden.
缇西 把帽子拿过来
Titsy, get the hat.
作为你们新的领袖
As your new leader
我现在宣布流放艾力提
I hereby banish Alakay...
他应当戴起这个代表耻辱的帽子
...he shell wear this hat of shame and...
离开水塘
leave the watering hole.
期限为一千年 或 一辈子
For a thousand years or life...
看哪个迟来
...whichever comes last.
唉 走开 走开
Come on. Shoo shoo. Get out of here.
你应该告诉我们的 儿子
You should have told us son.
你应该告诉我们你不是个真正的大王
You should have told us that you weren't a real king.
你可没说我得和人打架
You never told me that I have to fight anybody.
不然你想怎样?
What did you expect son?
我不知道 可能你可以作为父亲 给我一点建议呢
I don't know, maybe a fatherly advice,
- 比如 "儿子 那是个搏斗" - 但你是狮子 不是吗
- like: hey son...it's a fight. - You are a lion, aren't you?
但我从来没有跟其他狮子搏斗过
But I never fought another lion in my life.
当然没有 你是跳舞的嘛
Yeah, yes, right. You dance.
还有其他的事情 但重点是
And other stuff. The point is,
你的朋友麻昆加设计陷害了我
your pal, Makunga...set me up back there
- 这一切就不会发生了 如果... - 如果你是个真正的狮子
- I mean, none of these would happen... - If you were a real lion...
- 祖巴! - 是啊 我说了!
- Zuba. - Yeah, I said it.
真正的狮子?
A real lion?
谢了
Thanks.
太谢谢了
Thanks a lot.
锯子
Saw
针
stitcher.
擦汗 你挡住我的视线了 史蒂文
Swallow. You're in my light Steaven.
嗯 你肩上有个褐斑
Oh, say. You've got a brown spot there on your shoulder.
很好的观察力
Yeah, that's very observative of you Steven.
你该发现我全身都是褐斑
As you can see, I'm covered in brown spots.
好啦 骨头过几周就长好了 跟新的一样
OK. That bone will be good as new in a few weeks.
那我不需要去那个等死洞了?
So, I don't have to pick another dying hole?
当然不用 你还有大好的人生可以继续
No, Timo. You've got your whole life ahead of you.
- 真的吗 - 跑去玩吧
- Really?  - Go out there and grab a bite of that horns.
- 多谢你 医生 - 祝你好运
- Thank you doctor Mankiewicz. - Break a leg.
可爱的孩子
Sweet kid.
呃 那个褐斑像是巫医综合症
This spot looks like witch doctor's disease.
巫医综合症?
Witch doctor's disease?
我听过最荒唐的病 史蒂文
That's the most ridiculous disease, I've ever heard of, Steven.
别问
Wow... Don't ask.
有人挺淘气啊
Someone has been naughty.
- 可能有点疼 - 我们前任的巫医乔
- OK. This one will hurt a bit. - Joe, our last witch doctor,
也长了像那样的褐斑
he had a spot just like that.
周一乔还活着
Monday Joe
周三乔就没了
Wednesday no Joe.
- 周三乔就没了 - 可以呼吸了
- Wednesday no Joe?  - I can breathe.
多谢你 医生
Thanks doc.
巫医综合症是真事?
So, this witch doctor's disease is a real thing?
会找到治愈方法的嘿 你至少有48小时啦
You'll find a cure. Hey, you got at least forty eight hours.
但我从没听说这种病啊
But I have never even heard of it.
我可没有盘尼西林
What? I mean, I don't have any penicillin.
而最最基本的 我还必须得做个做X线断层扫描呀
I'm gonna need a catscan just to get started.
找只狮子帮你忙啊 他们肯定乐意
You'll have a lion looking over, they'd be happy to.
那家伙真是天才 难以置信
Ta daaa. That guy has got talent.
你们肯定没见过这个
Bet you haven't seen that one before.
纽约人看得五体投地
This knock 'em dead in New York.
- 咱们也试试吧 - 好啊 来
- Hey, let's all give it a try. - Yeah, let's do it.
等一下
Well, hey hey hey
想试就试吧 可得很多年才能练到这水平
I know you want to but it's gonna take years of practice you get never gonna quite get a tight stream...
等到练到嘴唇肌肉有力
until you build up your lip muscles to the point...
收缩到一起像这样 明白吗
...where you can purse your lips like this. You got it?
Ta daa...
你们怎么可能... 你们即学即会啊
How did you? You guys got it right up the box.
- 你能做 我们也能做 - 这流淌在我们的血液里
- If you can do it. We can do it. - It's in our blood.
我一直以为我有点特殊呢
I always thought, I was a little bit unique.
我们确实很特殊啊
We are unique.
大自然的力量创造了我们
Hey, we are like a force of nature.
百万个生命
A million points of light.
黑条纹
And all stripes.
完全一样
Exactly the same.
看起来非常惊人 科沃斯基
Looks impressive Kowalski,
能飞吗
but will it fly?
如果折这边 这边 那边 就能飞了
Yes, if we fold it here, here and here.
漂亮
Nice.
哦 老天爷啊
Oh man,
唉 老爸认为我是个完全的笨蛋
my dad thinks I'm a total loser.
我毁了我父母的生活
I have ruined my parent's lifes.
那可一点也不屌
That is definitely not crackalacking.
简直是超衰 伙计
It's lacking in the craken my friend.
我得弥补错误
I have got to fix this.
那个
So
有件事...
there is...
- 有事要告诉你们 - 嘿 伙计们
- there is something I gotto tell you. - Hey guys.
这地方简直是天堂 不是吗
Is this place great or what?
我选"不是吗"
I'd go with or what.
告诉你们 你们绝对不会相信 不过
Oh well, I tell you what. You're not gonna believe it but...
我和摩托摩托开始约会了
I got a date with Moto Moto.
谁是摩托摩托?
Who is Moto Moto.
他高大 英俊 很壮
Oh, he's so big and handsome and big.
你知道摩托摩托代表什么吗?
You know what Moto Moto means?
双胞胎?
Twins?
是"帅哥帅哥"
It means hot hot.
"帅哥帅哥"?
Hot hot?
好吧 你何时变得这么非洲本土化的?
OK, when did you start parley in African?
- 这流淌在我的血液里 - 别担心
- It's in my blood. - Don't worry.
你可以等我走了之后 再和帅哥调情
You can flirt around with Mr. Hot Pants after I'm gone.
为什么 梅尔曼 我在兴头上炫耀 你干嘛老泼冷水
What's the deal Melman? Why am I the parade and you are the rain?
那你为什么每次都在我这里炫耀
Why do you have to dry the parade under my rain?
那我下次在城市的另一区炫耀去了
Maybe I'll just parade myself in another part of town.
- 冷静冷静 - 随你便 不过主街是我的
- Fine by me. - By the way, the main streets mine.
- 去你的臭主街 归你就归你 - 去跟你那个帅哥混去吧
- Well, you can have your old stinking main streets. - And you can take your hottie tub flood and you Mr. hot, Moto Moto Jr. comes...
- 那个摩托摩托 - 你说什么呢
- My hottie tub what?  - What are you talking about?
- 这么乱啊 - 别吵了
Come on Melman
- 你为什么不告诉她就好了? - 要说你说去
- why don't you just tell her?  - You tell,
说什么? 说... 我不明白你说什么
what? Tell her, what are you talking about? I don't know what you are talking about.
- 好吧 我要走了 - 你知道么 不必麻烦了
- So I guess, I'll go then. - You know what, don't bother.
那就少找我麻烦!
Don't get up in my account.
不不不 梅尔曼 格洛丽娅
Melman, Gloria.
我还以为你们是朋友呢
Hey, I thought you guys were friends.
知道吗 马蒂说的是对的
Come on guys, Marty is absolutely right.
- 马蒂? - 马蒂?!
Marty? Marty?
马蒂?
Marty!
到底发生什么事了
What the heck is going on?
你不是... 哦 他是... 不! 我以为 他... 你不是... 他! 他...
You are not ooh.. He was no! I thought he...You are not him. He is ooh...
你以为那家伙是我
You thought that guy was me?
不 不是 其实 是啊 你们长得... 拜托
No, no, no. I mean yes, yes. You do guys, come on.
你以为我是他?
You thought I was him?
你们长得有点 很像
You guys do kind of look a little a lot you look a lot alike.
对吧 马蒂 你们长得很像 你们笑起来一样
Marty you look a lot alike, come on. You laugh alike, you talk alike,
说话也一样 语气也一样
he has the same sort of speech pattern...
斑纹也一样 有点奇怪 真的... 你们两个... 拜托 马蒂
I mean that is a little weird. Really, you two guys are, come on Marty.
看来我果然不是独一无二啊
So you're saying there is nothing unique about me
我和其他斑马没有区别
I am just like any other zebra.
你当然是与众不同的
No, of course you are different.
怎么不同?
How? How?
好吧 我分不清
OK. I can't tell you apart.
不过你可以戴个铃什么的
Maybe you could wear a bell or something. I don't know.
- 铃? - 不 不是铃 戴铃是个很烂的主意
- A bell?  - OK. not a bell, no bell is a bad idea.
不不 不如穿写着"我是傻瓜"的T恤吧
No, no, no. How about a t-shirt that says: "I'm with stupid."?
- 我不傻 - 你不傻 是他傻
- I am not stupid. - Not you stupid, him stupid!
你知道吗 你和那群马玩乐时
You know what? While you have been off doing prancing pony with the new pussy.
我正在经历差不多 生命里最惨的一天 满意了吗
I have been having pretty much the worst day of my life, OK?
事情都是围绕你转 对吧
It's always about you, isn't it?
我的问题只是比你的重要一点 马蒂
My problems are just a little bit bigger than yours Marty.
就算分不清你和别人 又怎样
All right, I couldn't tell you apart. So what?
行啊 走吧 马蒂 你只有这个在行
Yeah fine, run away Marty! Run away. That's what you do best,
跟在纽约时一样
just like back in New York!
我在这儿 不过你分不清楚 对吧
I'm right here. But you can't tell that right?
你真是百万里挑一的朋友
Your one in a million friend...
祝你继续自己一个人享受你的那个 "比任何其他人都重要的问题" !
hopes you enjoy your bigger than everyone else's problems, alone!
走就走吧 我不需要你帮我解决问题
Good, leave! I don't need you to help me solve my problems.
你们大同小异 我就是分不清楚 谁是马蒂又怎样 我不在乎
You know what? You diame dust I can't tell which one is Marty.
哪个是马蒂 等一下 哦 谁在乎
Oh, which one is Marty? Wait a minute, wait a minute, oh yeah! I don't care.
帽子真抢眼 你个臭显摆
Nice hat, you show off!
马蒂
Marty...
别走
Don't go.
看 莫里斯
Look Maurice.
是个好地方 我可以在此建造夏日行宫
Here is the perfect spot for my semi-palace
把坑填填 改改水道就行了
so please fill in all these holes and relocate the roofed.
谁把那么好看的头丢在地上了
Oh, who'd leave a perfectly good head lying around.
真浪费资源
What a waste.
跟我讲一讲 我在等死
Tell me about it. I'm in my prime here.
晚期不治
I'm terminal, you know.
可能只剩2天可活了
Probably only have another two days left to live.
那可真不幸
That's a bomber man.
如果我 朱利安国王
Oh, if I King Julien, that's my name.
只剩2天可活的话
Only had two days left to live.
会实现所有我梦想要做的事
I'd do all the things I have ever dreamed of doing.
什么事?
Like what?
我想成为职业口哨家
I'd love to became a professional whistler.
我现在已经非常令人惊艳了
I pretty amazing that I did know.
但我要好上加好
But I wanna get luck even better.
完全可以以此为生
I'd make my living out of it.
你知道我还会做什么其它事么
You know what else I'd do?
我要去侵略临国的地盘
I'd invade a neighboring country and impose...
不管他们愿意与否 都会强加我的意识形态予他们
...my own ideology even if they didn't want it.
你说得当然简单 你是个国王啊
It's easy for you to say, you are a king.
是的 你只是个可悲的小脑袋
Yes. And you are only just a sad little head.
但你在死前 肯定有想做的事
But there must be something you want to do before you die.
嗯 确实有件事
Well...There is this one thing.
什么事? 告诉我
What is it? Tell me.
呃 不行
Well. No, I couldn't.
是什么
I mean. What is it?
我从来都鼓不起勇气告诉格洛丽娅
You know, I just never really have the guts to tell Gloria,
- 我如何... - 告诉什么 告诉我啦
how I think about her.  What is it?
我从来不敢告诉格洛丽娅 我对她的感觉
I don't really have the guts to tell Gloria, how I feel about her. What is it?
- 我一直以来对她的感觉 - 嗯 不告诉我就算了
- I have always felt about her. - Fine, don't tell me!
是女人吗 你刚才没告诉我 我们现在谈的可是女人啊
Is it a woman? Oh, you didn't tell me we are talking about a woman.
你还在怕什么 你反正都快死了
What are you afraid of? You are dead man anyway, come on.
没错 是啊 你说对了
Yeah? Yeah...Yeah, you are right.
你一定要迈步向这女人走去
Well, you gotta march right up to this woman,
好吗 注视她的双眼
right? You look her right in the eye,
身体向前倾 好吧 低下身子
you lean forward, right? Just a little, almost all the way.
然后你让她向前倾 靠近你 是吧
Then you let her, like, lean forward, just a little bit until you're...
只剩一个嘴唇的距离
...just a lips distance away from each other.
然后你告诉她
And then you just tell her...
你有多恨她
how much you hate her.
啊 事实上
Actually, it's...
比较像是有多爱她
it's more like love her.
喔 你个多情种子
Oh, you slave dog.
你还真是个花花公子啊 知道吗
You're a real player, you know that?
现在听我说 你得举起她
Now listen to me. You gotto raise up.
听到了吗
I can't hear you.
- 听到了 - 很好 你把她举到空中
- Yeah. - Good. You gotto raise up.
举得高高的
raise..up..
- 你得从洞里出来 - 好
- You gotto get out of the hole.
把她从地上举起来
I'm raising up on the ground.
- 我在上升 莫里斯 - 继续往上
He's raising Maurice. - I'm raising Maurice.
- 要马上去找她 - 没错
- You gotto go right up to this woman.  -Yeah.
- 然后直奔主题 - 我要告诉她
- You gotto go right up to a fight. - Yeah, I tell her.
说出你的感受
And then you gotto say:
宝贝 我中意你
Baby, I dig you.
耶 我去告诉她 现在就去
Yeah. Yeah. I'm gonna do it. I'm gonna do it.
我喜欢那颗快乐的小脑袋
I love that happy little head.
她爱我
She loves me.
她爱我的眼睛
She loves my eyes.
她爱我
She loves me.
她爱我的过去
She loves my ass.
她爱我圆滚滚的身材
She loves my roundness.
她爱我的强壮
She loves that I'm chunky.
她爱我的丰满
She loves that I'm plumpy.
她爱我的嘻哈味道
She loves my healthiness.
她爱我的风趣
She loves my zestiness.
她永不停止的爱我
She loves me restlessly.
她永远的爱我
She loves me forever.
她爱我 因为她爱我
She loves me, because she loves me.
摩托摩托 在我们越陷越深之前
Moto Moto before things get too serious, well...
我想问你 如果说我留下来
I was wondering if I were to for example stay here...
我想问问
I'd like to ask you...
让你的心意通过丰满双唇 传达到我的金刚之颅中吧
Let your candy lips bring the messages to my ear canal.
我还有很多疑问
Well I don't know, I have so many questions.
我保证 答案永远是"是"
Well I promise, the answer will always be yes...
除非 需要说"不"
unless, no is required.
那... 你为什么被我吸引
OK. So, what is it about me that you find so interesting?  Oh...
你是我见过最丰满的女人
you're the most plumpiness girl I've ever met.
好啊 还有呢?
OK. Other than that?
我想想
Let's see,
你最壮
you, you know, you are chunky.
哦
Right.
我的天啊 你很胖
Oh, my gosh girl you are huge.
你说过了
You've said that.
是啊 不用往下讲了吧
Oh, yes right. We don't have to talk no more.
格洛丽娅?!
Gloria!
- 格洛丽娅? - 梅尔曼?
- Gloria?  - Melman?
梅尔曼
Melman
这位是摩托摩托
I want you to meet with Moto Moto.
摩托摩托 很高兴... 很高兴见到你
Ah, Moto Moto. Yeah. Nice to, nice to meet you.
我 其实
Well, I guess, I...
没关系 我接受你的道歉
It's OK. Melman. Apology accepted.
哦 是啊 没错 这就是我过来的原因
Oh, yeah, right, yes. That, yes, that's why I... Good.
那就好 那我...
Oh, OK. That's well, that's it then.
好了就走吧 我们正忙着呢
You good, we're kind of a busy here man.
不 不是这件事
No! No, that's not it!
听着 摩托摩托 你最好像女皇一样待这位女士
Listen Mototo, you'd better treat this lady like a queen.
因为 我的朋友 你找到了完美的女人 朋友
Because you my friend, you found yourself the perfect woman.
我若像你样幸运
If I was ever so lucky to find the perfect woman
我会天天送她花束
I would give her flowers every day.
而且不是随便什么破花
And not just any flowers, OK?
她最喜欢白色的兰花
Her favorites are orchids. White.
要在早餐送到床边 六条全麦面包 正反两面都涂黄油
And breakfast in bed. Six loaves of wheat toast with butter on both sides.
不要面包皮 她喜欢这样的做法
No crusts. The way she likes it.
我会借她肩膀哭 成为她最好的朋友
I'd be her shoulder to cry on and her best friend...
整天都想怎么让她欢笑
and I'd spend every day trying to think of how to make her laugh.
她有世界上最动听的笑声
She has the most...most amazing laugh.
我是说 我要是你就那么做
Well, I mean. That's what I would do, if I were you.
可我不是你 你最好乖乖做
But I'm not. So you do it.
呃 嗯... 什么?
Oh, OK. What?
真让人感动
That was beautiful.
随他去吧 刚才说到哪里?
Anyways, where were we?
我很胖
I'm huge.
很惊讶看到我吗 麻昆加 我来把事情弄清楚
Surprised to see me Makunga? Well I'm here to set things straight.
像真正的狮子一样 这个够劲吗 这个呢
Like a real lion. Is this real enough for you? How about this?
这一拳打你胆敢玩阴的
This is for setting me up.
这一拳打你抢了我老爸的工作
This is for stealing my dad's job.
这一拳打你让我全家受辱 像傻瓜样被人耻笑
This is for humiliating my family. And making me fun like a fool.
打够了? 滚吧
Had enough? Sure fly away.
胆小鬼
Coward.
水没有了
The water, it's gone.
- 哦 不 - 水塘从没干过
- Oh no. - The watering hole has never gone dry before.
- 我们需要很多等死洞了 - 怎么会这样?
- We're gonna need a lot more dying holes. - How could this happen?
都闪一边去 到底发生什么事了
Out of my way. What is going on here?
水干了 我们就一个人喝水都不够了
The watering hole is dried up, there's barely enough water for one of us.
- 好观察力 雪莉 - 我是斑比
- Yes, good observation Shirley. - I'm Boby.
- 麻昆加 我们该怎么办? - 安静!
- Makunga what will we do?  - Quiet!
听着 我想 恐怕只有一个方法 能解决这可怕的危机
Listen up. I'm afraid there is only one solution to this horrible crisis.
- 我们得竞争水源 - 竞争?
- We'll all have to fight for it.  - Fight for it?
这主意太疯狂了
This is crazy.
这不公平 你肯定赢
That's not fair, you'd win.
- 没错 雪莉 - 我是斑...
- Exactly Shirley. - I'm Boby.
对不起 伙计们 人生本来就不公平
Sorry folks, but life isn't fair.
现在我是领袖 这要多谢谢跳舞的狮子艾力提
I'm in charge now. Thanks to Alakay, the dancing lion.
求你了 麻昆加 这是保护区唯一的水源
Please Makunga this is the only water on the reserve.
如果你渴 你得去保护区外找水喝
If you're thirsty you'll have to look for water off the reserve.
去保护区外?
Off the reserve?
- 从没人离开保护区存活的 - 我离开过
- No one leave the reserve and survived. - I left the reserve...
也存活了
and survived.
我可以帮忙 好像是水道堵了
I could do something about this. Looks like a clogged pipe.
纽约常有这种事
But we get in New York all the time.
- 只要逆流而上 - 逆流而上? 去保护区外?
- I'll just travel up river.  - Up river? Off the reserve?
你?
You?
是我 我能疏通水道 带回水源
Yeah me. I'll unclog the pipe and bring back your water.
太好了 我想帮你收拾行李 不过看到那帽子
Great I'll help you pack but by the looks of that hat...
我想你应该准备好了
I see you're all set.
好吧 笑啊 笑掉大牙吧
Yeah fine. Go ahead laugh. Laugh your mane off.
我会证明你是错的
I'm gonna prove you're wrong.
说不定 你应该试着跳个祈雨舞
May be you should try a little rain dance.
如果是祖巴 肯定知道该怎么办 祖巴在哪呢?
Zuba would know what to do. Where is Zuba?
- 你根本不管我们死活 - 祖巴才应该是领袖 不是你
- You don't care about us. - Zuba should be in charge, not you.
祖巴在哪里
Where is Zuba?
好了 够了 因为情况特殊
Alright, fine. As an added measure
我会咨询祖巴的
I will consult with Zuba.
马蒂?
Marty?
嘿 马蒂?
Hi! Marty?
马蒂?
Marty?
抱歉 打扰一下
Excuse me,Excuse me!
嗨 马蒂在吗?
Hi! Is...is Marty in there?
马蒂 有人看见马蒂了吗?
Marty? Is there anyone see Marty?
这样吧 如果见到他了
All right! Well...if you see him
就说他朋友艾力克斯来和他道别了
Tell my friend,Alex came and say goodbye!
- 说再见? - 再见
- goodbye? - Goodbye!
别走 你去哪儿 我们也能去吗
Don't go! Can we come?
不用了 这是我必须要独自去解决的事情
No! No! It's something have to do alone!
马蒂 我知道你在这儿
Marty? I know you're there!
在走之前 我有话对你说
Before I go,I've got something want to say.
你是个很好的朋友
You've been a great friend.
总让我看到我问题的光亮面
我却没想到你也会有烦心事
你需要我时 我却不在你身边
像在动物园时一样
Just like that zoo.
我还算什么朋友? 很糟糕吧
What kind of a friend does that make me? Pretty lousy friend I guess.
我只想告诉你 你是百万里挑一的
Well I just want you to know that...you're one in a million.
讲得真好 太让人感动了
Isn't this touching? This is touching.
拜托你转过身来 我想当面对你说
So could you please turn around so I can tell you that to your face?
没错 找到你了 我看见了
That's right. Got you. I see you in there.
对 就是你
Yeah yeah you. That's right you, right there.
第12排 左手边第203个
Twelfth row, two hundred and third from the left.
马蒂 找到了 我知道那是你
I see you Marty. I know it's you.
你知道是什么让你那么特殊吗?
You know what makes you special?
这些家伙是白底黑条
These guys...They're white with black stripes.
你是黑底白条
You're black with white stripes.
你是个梦想家 一直都是
You're a dreamer Marty. Always have been.
音乐方面很有品位
You have a great taste in music and...
朋友方面就不怎么样
horrible taste in friends.
格洛丽娅 梅尔曼不算 就是我而已
Not Melman and Gloria, me.
好 算我一个
OK. I'm in.
不行 马蒂 你不能去
No Marty. You can't come with me.
我不信你还有选择
I don't believe you have a choice.
有水吗?
Any water?
没有 只有更多的钻石和金块
No, just more diamonds and gold.
好吧 别放弃
OK. Don't give up hope.
大家都听着 我可以帮你们
Listen up. I'll help you.
只有一个方法能弄到珍贵的水源
There is only one way to get your precious water.
我 你们爱戴的国王朱利安
I, your beloved King Julien,
将无私地用我的好朋友
must simply make a small sacrifice to my good friends,
祭祀水神们 地点就在...
water gods.
在火山里
In the volcano.
要做什么?
What does that do?
要做什么? 真是个好问题
What does that do? Excellent question.
我的祭祀贡品跳入岩浆
My sacrifice goes into volcano.
友好的水神吃掉贡品
Then the friendly gods eat up my sacrifice.
好吃 谢谢你的贡品
Mmm.. Very nice. Thank you for the sacrifice.
要不再来一个
Please have another sacrifice.
不了 今天的量够了
No, I've had enough for the day.
如果你不再来一个 我会很难...
Listen, I'm gonna be very unsettled unless you will have another...
我不想再吃了 行吗
I don't want another sacrifice, OK?
你看看你 这么瘦
Look at you, you look skinny.
我吃饱了 明白了吗
No, I think I've had enough, is that clear?
水神吃掉贡品后
The gods eat the sacrifice,
他们会很感激 就会给我一些水
they are grateful, they give me some of their water.
- 然后我把水给你们 - 什么?
- Then I give it to you. - What?
- 真能行吗 - 不 我是说 当然能
- Does it work?  - No. I mean yes.
是吧 莫里斯
Well, Maurice?
一半一半啦
Yeah, it's fifty fifty.
好极了
Excellent.
现在只要找一个动物 自愿跳进岩浆
Now, all I  need is someone who'd like to go in the volcano and...
做水神的食物
get eaten by gods.
有人自愿去吗 有人举手吗 我需要个志愿者
Any hands? Hands? Anybody? OK. I need someone...
像是从来都没人爱的
perhaps who has never fall in love.
他可以直视死亡 成为真正的英雄
Who could look death, straight in the eye ball. A real genuine hero.
- 我来 - 梅尔曼?
- I'll do it. - Melman?
快点 在我们恢复理智以前
Hurry up. Before you all come to your senses.
梅尔曼 你到底有什么问题?
Melman, what is wrong with you?
我反正都要死了
I'm dying anyways.
只要有机会为你找到水 就值得
If there is a chance, it'll get you water, it'll be worthy.
你傻了吗?
Are you nuts?
格洛丽娅 我想告诉你 我们在动物园的时候
Gloria, I just want you to know, back at the zoo...
不是医生或处方让我生存 而一直是你
it was never the doctors or the prescriptions that kept me going...it was always you.
只要能天天看到你
Seeing you every day.
那就是我活着的动力
That's what kept me going.
梅尔曼 等等
Melman, wait.
你要一天到晚都拉着这张脸么
You gonna mop around like this all day?
别冲我哼 听我说 祖巴
Don't hmph me. Listen Zuba.
奇迹已经发生了 我们的孩子回到了我们的身边
A miracle happened. Our son has come back to us.
- 难道这还不够吗? - 你想说什么 女人
- How come, that is not good enough for you? - What are you saying woman?
我们已经失去他一次了 祖巴
We've lost him once Zuba.
别再失去第二次了
Let's not lose him again.
祖巴
Zuba!
- 祖巴 - 走开
- Zuba. - Get out of here.
- 你想干什么 麻昆加? - 糟糕了
- What do you want Makunga? - It's awful.
水塘水全干了
The watering hole is dried up.
全干了 那不可能
Dried up? That's impossible.
一滴都不剩
There is nothing left.
你是领头狮子 麻昆加 你打算怎么做
Well, you are the alpha lion Makunga. What are you gonna do about it?
你儿子艾力提说他能解决 他离开保护区了
Your son, Alakay. He said he could fix it. He has gone up river.
- 离开保护区了? - 不
- Off the reserve? - No!
我试图把他拦下 我跟他说这简直是自杀
I tried to stop him. I told him it was suicide...
可他说他要证明给你看
but he was determined to prove himself to you.
你在这等着 说不定他会回来
You stay here in case he comes back.
赶快 祖巴!
Hurry Zuba.
太感动了
I'm so parched.
这地方就是为了吓人才存在的么
Is this place, aren't affright you out?
悄悄的 把问题解决了
We'll slip in, find the problem.
猎人永远也不会发现我们来过这儿
Hunters'll never know we were here.
为什么做这件事的是我们?
Why are "we" doing this?
听着 马蒂 说不定我老爸他会...
Look, Marty maybe my dad'll think that I'm...
我只想证明 我是真正的狮子
I just wanna show him, I'm a real lion.
而不是巧克力狮子?
As opposed to a chocolate lion.
我知道这很难让人相信
I know this might sound hard to believe,
但是很明显 狮子们是不跳舞的
but apparently lions don't dance.
什么?!
What?
至少我老爸这样想
As far as my dad's concerned.
人类可认为你是跳舞天才
As far as the people is concerned, you're a huge hit.
那是纽约 这是非洲 要求更严苛
That was New York. This is Africa. It's a much tougher crowd.
马蒂 马蒂 就是这里
Marty, Marty. This's it.
被堵上的水源
This is the clog.
快来
Come on.
找到水了
Here's the water.
马蒂 低头 看那边
Marty, stay down. Look at that.
那个女人
It's her.
- 这样对吗 - 做得很好
- Is this right? - Oh, very good.
娜娜 讲慢点
你还没上手是吧
我们需要炸药 你有炸药吗
We need dynamite, do you have any dynamite?
哦 糟糕 我今早刚用完最后一根火柴
Oh, snap, I just used my last...
快走
我不想死
- 快快 - 曲折盘旋
不不
曲折盘旋
不
艾力克斯?
Alex!
- 快跑 马蒂 - 我不能把你丢在这
- Run Marty. - Come on, I can't leave you here.
快跑 去叫救兵
Go, get help.
好了
OK.
好吧
OK. OK...
来吧 没问题的
OK. Here we go. OK...
好吧 好吧
Here we go. Here we go.
为什么跳舞呀
What is all the hoop about?
- 乔 - 乔 巫医吗?
- Joe? -Joe, the witch doctor?
- 我们还以为你死了 - 我也以为是这样
- We thought you were dead. - So did I.
后来我想明白 我本来就全身褐斑
Then I realized, I'm covered in brown spots.
那梅尔曼不会死
So, Melman's not dying.
- 梅尔曼不会死 - 借过 让让 梅尔曼
- Melman's not dying. - Excuse me, excuse me. Melman!
让开
Move out.
别往下跳
Don't do this.
朱利安 停下 这太疯狂了
Julien, stop this. This's crazy!
让长颈鹿跳下岩浆来求水 太疯狂了
Oh, certainly throwing a giraffe into a volcano to make water is crazy.
是的
Yes!
求你了 梅尔曼 别跳!
Please, Melman stop.
- 格洛丽娅? - 你不能那么做
- Gloria? - You can't do this.
- 为什么不能? - 因为 啊
- Why not? - Because I...
- 你不能这么做 - 首先 这真的很痛啊!
- You can't do this Melman. - First of all, it hurts.
第二 我反正只有18小时活了
Second of all, I'll only have eighteen hours to live anyway.
梅尔曼 我必须要知道
Melman, I gotto know.
你说的那些话都是认真的吗?
Did you really mean all those things you said about me?
当然是
Of course I did.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
是吗?
It is?
太疯狂了 我环游世界半圈
It's crazy in the thing, I had to go half way around the world...
才发现真命天子
to find out that the perfect guy for me...
一直就在我隔壁
lived right next door.
我猜你说的是你和我 邻居
Then I guess it's you and me neighbor...
一起度过接下来的18小时
you and me for the next eighteen hours.
不过多久 我会一直陪着你
I'll take whatever you got.
- 莫里斯 事情怎么变这样? - 我相信 这胖女士有灵魂
- Maurice, what just happened? - I believe the fat lady has sobbed.
- 这里发生什么事了? - 嘿 马蒂?
- Hey, what's going on here?  - Marty. Hey!
听着 艾力克斯遇到了大麻烦 我们得立刻去救他
Listen up. Alex is in big trouble. We get to get up the river fast.
- 用飞机吧 - 好主意 快来
- What about the plane? - Perfect. Come on.
我们不会继续修飞机 除非你答应一切条件
The plane won't be fixed until the suits meet our demands.
现在 关于产假...
Now, about maternity leave.
产假? 你是个男人啊
Maternity leave? You're males.
听着 我们得用飞机去救人
Look, we need a plane for rescue mission.
不把工会摆平 什么都做不成
Well, there is nothing I can do until we bust up this union.
不让用飞机 我就把你们都摆平
I'm gonna get the busty not bully you if you don't get this plane going.
你没发现我也焦头烂额吗
Can't you see these commies have my hands tied here?
不许有产假
No maternity leave.
可能有某人不希望 让这些照片流传在外呢
Maybe a certain someone wouldn't want these blowing around on the savannah.
行了 你休你的产假吧
All right, you get your maternity leave.
总算好了
Finally.
我们要去哪里? 发生了什么事?
Where are you headed? What's going on? Where are we going?
哦 不 不要把我放到火上
Oh no, please. You are not gonna burn me there.
不 别这样
No, no, no. This's wrong.
看 你们都是幸存者
You see? You are survivals.
现在 想不想吃烤狮子?
Now, how about a nice lion casserole?
你不能吃狮子
We can't eat a lion.
别担心 吃起来像是鸡肉 快来
Don't worry, taste like chicken.
不 别听她瞎说
No, no, no, no. Don't listen to her.
她神智不清醒 同志们
She is out of her mind. People.
我也是从纽约来的
I'm from New York City too.
是我呀 中央公园的狮子艾力克斯
It's me, Alex the lion. From Central Park.
老爸?
Dad.
你想什么呢 你根本无能力存活
What were you thinking son? You got no matter be not here.
好了 你躲到我身后
This's it, I want you to stay behind.
不 爸爸 他们是纽约人 都是胆小怕事的人
Look dad, they're New Yorkers, they are just...ruined and frightened people.
躲到后面
Stay back.
别让他们跑了
Are you gonna let them get away?
你在干什么 儿子?
What are you doing son?
做我唯一会做的事
The only thing I know how to do.
这些舞蹈动作 是艾力克斯?
Hey, all those moves... Alex?
- 是艾力克斯 那只狮子 - 中央公园那只
- This is Alex the lion. - From Central Park. This is Alex.
只有一只狮子能这么跳舞
Only one lion can move like that.
- 真棒 - 简直不能相信
- This is beautiful. - I can't believe this.
他是怎么做到的?
How does he do that?
- 老爸 你在干嘛? - 和我儿子一起跳舞
- Dad, what are you doing? - Dancing with my son...
- 我想... - 别想 老爸 用心感受
- I think. - Don't think dad, feel.
蝴蝶
Butterfly.
我也会
I'm doing it. I'm doing it.
真精彩啊
Oh, that was beautiful.
好了 该开伙了
Now, let's eat.
老爸 小心
Dad, look out!
- 什么东西? - 艾力克斯 进来
- What the? - Alex, get in.
她有枪 我们能跑就得得赶紧跑
She has got a gun. Let's get out while we can.
什么?
What?
她有枪 我们能跑就得得赶紧跑
She has got a gun. Let's get out while we can.
传话上去
Pass it on.
他说 我们开心一下
He said, let's have some fun and...
弄垮水坝 传话上去
take out the dam. Pass it on.
老大
Skipper
艾力克斯想弄垮水坝
Alex wants to take out the dam.
行啊 但那会是他的葬礼
Alright, but it's his funeral.
什么?
What?
- 同意 - 是 机长
- Deploy. - Aye aye, Skippy.
回来 那是我的晚餐
Come back. That's my dinner.
科沃斯基 全速飞行
Kovalski, full proto.
音乐
Music.
- 噢 我喜欢这歌 - 永远都不过时
- Oh, I like this song. - It never gets old.
确实很琅琅上口 掉头 降低
It does have a catchy hook.
往上飞 要不然我们死定了
Tell them, no, pull up. She will kill us.
肯定有别的路可走 传话上去
There is gotto be another way. Pass it on.
他说不要往上飞
They say, no pull up, kill us.
- 没有其它路了 传话上去 - 你确定?
- There is no other way. Pass it on. - Are you sure?
别人牺牲才是最伟大的
There is no sacrifice greater then someone else.
不 急救人员!
No, medic!
全力加速
Relic speed.
来吧
Bring it on.
坏猫咪们
Bad kitties.
不知道为什么祭祀不起作用
I don't know why the sacrifice didn't work.
这是有科学依据的
The science seem so solid.
我跳进岩浆
I'd jump right in that volcano...
你知道 我对吹口哨不在行
if I wasn't so good at whistling.
- 是你们 终于找到你们了 - 默特?
- Oh, it's you. I found you. - Mort?
- 哦 不知道水神喜不喜欢海鲜? - 马上就知道了
- I wonder if the gods like seafood. - Let's go find out.
看 莫里斯
Look, Maurice.
- 还真快 - 我成功了 成功了
- That was quick. - I did it. I did it. I did it.
好吧 你成功了
OK. You did it. Oh yes.
看
Look.
是艾力提和祖巴
It's Alakay, it's Zuba.
祖巴 艾力提
Zuba, Alakay.
我真高兴 你们平安回来
You're back. I'm so glad you're safe.
别挡着我的路
Out of my way.
看看 看看
Well, well, well, well, well.
如果我没记错 祖巴 你荣誉的退位了
You know Zuba, if I remember correctly, you quitted the pride,
而你 是被赶走的
and you were kicked out.
想都不要想 别以为弄到水
So don't think for any instant that...
就能改变任何事
this changes anything.
你说得对 事实上 我们歉卑的 送给你这个手包表示感谢
You're right, in fact we humbly present you with this token of appreciation.
男士包 在纽约非常流行
That is a man bag, very popular where I came from.
- 我都不知该说什么好了 - 可以把随身物都装进去 肯定很酷
- I don't know what to say. - You can still be tough and carry your stuff.
是啊 链子还能调啊
Does this strip adjust?
我去远足时带上它一定很帅
Yes. I think this will go very nicely for me when I go out hiking.
但恐怕你还是被流放的
But I'm afraid you're still banished.
就知道你会这么说
We figured you'd say that.
我的手提包
My hand bag.
你这坏猫咪
You bad kitty.
不要
你应得的 儿子
You deserve this son.
欢迎任职
Welcome to the pride.
谢谢你 老爸
Thanks dad.
但这是属于你的
But this belongs to you.
不 孩子 是我们的
No, no son, to us.
我的儿子 纽约之王
My son, the king of New York!
这才是我的宝贝
That's my baby!
爱可以超越一切差异
Love transcends all differences.
今天我们聚到一起 来庆祝这样的爱情
We are gathered here today to celebrate such a love.
你俩是否愿意与对方祸福与共
Do you take each other, for better or for worse?
希望是福
For better please.
多么漂亮又奇怪的一对啊
What a beautiful weird couple.
不可能坚持很久的
That's not gonna last.
我可以吻新娘吗 老大
Can I kiss the bride Skipper?
不行 放音乐
No. Music.
- 电力 - 检查完毕
- Struts? - Checked.
- 仪器 - 检查完毕
- Fillets? - Checked.
- 钻石黄金 - 检查完毕
- Diamonds and gold? - Checked.
新婚
- 拜拜 - 会想你们的
- Bye bye. - We're gonna miss you.
回见
See you later.
我们在蒙迪卡罗度完蜜月就回来
We'll be back after the honeymoon in Monte Carlo.
或者金子用光以后
Or whenever the gold runs out.
- 路上小心 - 早点回来
- Take cares. - Come back soon.
老妈 让他们慢慢玩吧
Hey you know mom, let them take their time.
纽约跑不了 对吧 伙计们?
New York is not going anywhere. Right guys?
没错
Yeah, you're right about that?
只要和她在一起
Well, as long as I'm with her.
还有你们两个 我不在乎到底在哪
And you two. I don't care where we're.
她拥有世界上最动听的笑声
She has the most amazing laugh.
爱无国界
Love has no boundaries.
看来还要再打扰你们一阵了
Well, it looks like you're stucked with us for a while.
老爸
Dad...
怎么了 我以为我们可以多聚一会儿
what's wrong? I just thought we could hang out a bit and...
- 吓着我了 - 我吓着你了 儿子
- You got me. - I got you son.
吓着我了 用我的拿手好戏
You got me with my... You did my thing. You got a background on me.
我喜欢那个
I love it.
我唬住你了 儿子
I got you son.
老爸还挺厉害 马蒂
Old man is not too bad, hey Marty?
马蒂? 谁是马蒂?
Marty? Who's Marty?
- 别装了 - 我不认识马蒂 别叫我马蒂
- Come on? - I don't know Marty. Don't call me Marty.
你骗不了我的
You can't fool me.
我没看到马蒂 这儿没有马蒂
I don't see no Marty. Ain't no Marty here.
马蒂 我可以看着你的眼睛
Marty, I can look into your eyes...
我知道 就是你
and I know it's you.
#Hey shake the hot thing. Shake the hot thing.
#Shake 'em. Shake 'em. Shake 'em. Shake 'em...